<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<entries>
   <entry id="1">
       <title>A Spatial Data Structure for Fast Poisson-Disk Sample Generation</title>
       <year>2006</year>
       <authors>
          <author>Greg Humphreys</author>
	  <author>Daniel Dunbar</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
           Sampling distributions with blue noise characteristics are 
           widely used in computer graphics. Although Poisson-disk 
           distributions are known to have excellent blue noise char-
           acteristics, they are generally regarded as too computationally 
           expensive to generate in real time. We present a new 
           method for sampling by dart-throwing in <i>O</i>(<i>N</i> log <i>N</i>) time 
           and introduce a novel and efficient variation for generating
           Poisson-disk distributions in <i>O</i>(<i>N</i>) time and space
       </abstract>
       <keywords>poisson,sampling</keywords>
       <pdf>library/antimony.pdf</pdf>
       <www>http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~gfx/pubs/antimony/</www>
   </entry>
   <entry id="2">
       <title>Efficient generation of poisson-disk sampling patterns</title>
       <year>2006</year>
       <authors>
          <author>Thouis Jones</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle>Efficient generation of poisson-disk sampling patterns. 2006. 
           <i>Journal of Graphics Tools, to appear.</i></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
           Poisson Disk sampling patterns are of interest to the graphics community 
	   because their blue-noise properties are desirable in sampling patterns
           for rendering, illumination, and other computations. Until now, such patterns 
	   could only be generated by slow methods with poor convergence, or
           could only be approximated by jittering individual samples or tiling sets
           of samples.<br/>
           We present a simple and efficient randomized algorithm for generating
           true Poisson Disk sampling patterns in a square domain, given a minimum
           radius <i>R</i> between samples. The algorithm runs in <i>O</i>(<i>N</i> log <i>N</i>) time for
           a pattern of <i>N</i> points. The method is based on the Voronoi diagram.
           Source code is available online.
       </abstract>
       <keywords>poisson,sampling</keywords>
       <pdf>library/JonesPoissonPreprint.pdf</pdf>
       <www>http://people.csail.mit.edu/thouis/</www>
   </entry>
   <entry id="3">
       <title>Faster Photon Map Global Illumination</title>
       <authors>
          <author>Per H. Christensen</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
           The photon map method is an extension of ray tracing that makes 
	   it able to efficiently compute caustics and soft indirect 
	   illumination on surfaces and in participating media. This paper 
	   describes a method to further speed up the computation of soft 
	   indirect illumination (diffuse-diffuse light transport such as 
	   color bleeding) on surfaces. The speedup is based on the 
	   observation that the many look-ups in the global photon map 
	   during final gathering can be simplified by precomputing local 
	   irradiance values at the photon positions.  Our tests indicate 
	   that the calculation of soft indirect illumination during 
	   rendering, which is the most time-consuming part, can be sped 
	   up by a factor of 5-7 in typical scenes at the expense of 1) a 
	   precomputation that takes about 2%-5% of the time saved during 
	   rendering and 2) a 28% increase of memory use.
       </abstract>
       <keywords>photon mapping</keywords>
       <pdf>library/Christensen: Faster Photon Map Global Illumination.pdf</pdf>
       <www>http://www.seanet.com/~myandper/abstract/jgt99.htm</www>
   </entry>
   <entry id="4">
       <title>An Anisotropic Phong BRDF Model</title>
       <year>2000</year>
       <authors>
          <author>Michael Ashikhmin</author>
          <author>Peter Shirley</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle>Ashikhmin, M., Shirley, P. "An Anisotropic Phong BRDF Model" <i>Journal of Graphics Tools</i>,  v.5, no. 2 (2000), pp.25-32.</fulltitle>
       <abstract>
           We present a BRDF model that combines several advantages of the 
	   various empirical models currently in use. In particular, it has 
	   intuitive parameters, is anisotropic, conserves energy, is 
	   reciprocal, has an appropriate non-Lambertian diffuse term, and 
	   is well-suited for use in Monte Carlo renderers.
       </abstract>
       <keywords>anisotropic,BRDF,Phong,reflection models</keywords>
       <pdf>library/Ashikhmin and Shirley: An Anisotropic Phong BRDF Model.pdf</pdf>
       <www>http://www.cs.utah.edu/~michael/brdfs/</www>
   </entry>
   <entry id="5">
       <title>Spherical Q<sup>2</sup>-tree for Sampling Dynamic Environment Sequences</title>
       <year>2005</year>
       <authors>
          <author>Liang Wan</author>
          <author>Tien-Tsin Wong</author>
          <author>Chi-Sing Leung</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
           Previous methods in environment map sampling seldom consider 
	   a sequence of dynamic environment maps. The generated sampling 
	   patterns of the sequence may not maintain the temporal 
	   illumination consistency and result in choppy animation. 
	   In this paper, we propose a novel approach, spherical 
	   Q<sup>2</sup>-tree, to address this consistency problem. 
	   The local adaptive nature of the proposed method suppresses 
	   the abrupt change in the generated sampling patterns over 
	   time, hence ensures a smooth and consistent illumination. 
	   By partitioning the spherical surface with simple curvilinear 
	   equations, we construct a quadrilateral-based quadtree over 
	   the sphere. This Q<sup>2</sup>-tree allows us to adaptively 
	   sample the environment based on an importance metric and 
	   generates low-discrepancy sampling patterns. No time-consuming 
	   relaxation is required. The sampling patterns of a dynamic 
	   sequence are rapidly generated by making use of the summed 
	   area table and exploiting the coherence of consecutive frames. 
	   From our experiments, the rendering quality of our sampling 
	   pattern for a static environment map is comparable to previous 
	   methods. However, our method produces smooth and consistent 
	   animation for a sequence of dynamic environment maps, even 
	   the number of samples is kept constant over time.  
       </abstract>
       <keywords></keywords>
       <pdf>library/q2tree.pdf</pdf>
   </entry>
   <entry id="6">
       <title>Direct Ray Tracing of Displacement Mapped Triangles</title>
       <year></year>
       <authors>
          <author>Brian Smits</author>
          <author>Peter Shirley</author>
          <author>Michael M. Stark</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
           We present an algorithm for ray tracing displacement 
	   maps that requires no ad- ditional storage over the 
	   base model. Displacement maps are rarely used in ray 
	   tracing due to the cost associated with storing and 
	   intersecting the displaced geometry. This is 
	   unfortunate because displacement maps allow the 
	   addition of large amounts of geometric complexity 
	   into models. Our method works for models composed of 
	   triangles with normals at the vertices. In addition, 
	   we discuss a special purpose displacement that creates 
	   a smooth surface that interpolates the triangle 
	   vertices and normals of a mesh. The combination allows 
	   relatively coarse models to be displacement mapped and 
	   ray traced effectively.
       </abstract>
       <keywords></keywords>
       <pdf>library/Smits and Shirley: Direct Ray Tracing of Displacement Mapped Triangles.pdf</pdf>
   </entry>
   <entry id="7">
       <title>Optimized View Frustum Culling Algorithms for Bounding Boxes</title>
       <year>2000</year>
       <authors>
          <author>Ulf Assarsson</author>
          <author>Tomas Möller</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
             This paper presents optimizations for faster view frustum 
	     culling (VFC) for axis aligned bounding box (AABB) and 
	     oriented bounding box (OBB) hierarchies. We exploit 
	     frame-to-frame coherency by caching and by comparing 
	     against previous distances and rotation angles. By using an 
	     octant test, we potentially halve the number of plane 
	     tests needed, and we also evaluate masking, which is a 
	     well-known technique. The optimizations can be used for 
	     arbitrary bounding volumes, but we only present results 
	     for AABBs and OBBs. In particular, we provide solutions 
	     which is 2-11 times faster than other VFC algorithms for 
	     AABBs and OBBs, depending on the circumstances.
       </abstract>
       <keywords></keywords>
       <pdf>library/vfcullbox.pdf</pdf>
   </entry>
   <entry id="8">
       <title>A Rapid Hierarchical Rendering Technique for Translucent Materials</title>
       <year></year>
       <authors>
          <author>Henrik Wann Jensen</author>
          <author>Juan Buhler</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
           This paper introduces an efficient two-pass rendering technique for   
           translucent materials. We decouple the computation of irradiance     
           at the surface from the evaluation of scattering inside the material.
           This is done by splitting the evaluation into two passes, where the  
           first pass consists of computing the irradiance at selected points on 
           the surface. The second pass uses a rapid hierarchical integration   
           technique to evaluate a diffusion approximation based on the 
	   irradiance samples. This approach is substantially faster than previous  
           methods for rendering translucent materials, and it has the advan-   
           tage that it integrates seamlessly with both scanline rendering and  
           global illumination methods. We show several images and animations 
	   from our implementation that demonstrate that the approach     
           is both fast and robust, making it suitable for rendering translucent
           materials in production                                              
       </abstract>
       <keywords>subsurface scatterring, BSSRDF, global illumination, diffusion theory, reflection models, translucent</keywords>
       <pdf>library/Wann Jensen: A Rapid Hierarchical Rendering Technique for Translucent Materials.pdf</pdf>
       <www>http://graphics.ucsd.edu/~henrik/papers/fast_bssrdf/</www>
   </entry>
   <entry id="9">
       <title>Structured Importance Sampling of Environment Maps</title>
       <year>2003</year>
       <authors>
          <author>Sameer Agarwal</author>
          <author>Ravi Ramamoorthi</author>
          <author>Serge Belongie</author>
          <author>Henrik Wann Jensen</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle>Reference: Sameer Agarwal, Ravi Ramamoorthi, Serge Belongie, and Henrik Wann Jensen: "Structured Importance Sampling of Environment Maps". Proceedings of SIGGRAPH'2003.</fulltitle>
       <abstract>
             We introduce structured importance sampling, a new technique for 
	     efficiently rendering scenes illuminated by distant natural 
	     illumination given in an environment map. Our method handles 
	     occlusion, high-frequency lighting, and it is significantly 
	     faster than alternative methods based on Monte Carlo sampling. 
	     We achieve this speedup as a result of several ideas. First, 
	     we present a new metric for stratifying and sampling an 
	     environment map taking into account both the illumination 
	     intensity as well as the expected variance due to occlusion within 
	     the scene. We then present a novel hierarchical stratification 
	     algorithm that uses our metric to automatically stratify the 
	     environment map into regular strata. This approach enables a number 
	     of rendering optimizations, such as pre-integrating the illumination 
	     within each stratum to eliminate noise at the cost of adding bias, 
	     and sorting the strata to reduce the number of sample rays. We have 
	     render ed several scenes illuminated by natural lighting, and our 
	     results indicate that structured importance sampling is better than 
	     the best previous Monte Carlo techniques, requiring one to two 
	     orders of magnitude fewer samples for the same image quality.
       </abstract>
       <keywords></keywords>
       <pdf>library/structured-importance-sampling.pdf</pdf>
       <www>http://graphics.ucsd.edu/~henrik/papers/structured/</www>
   </entry>
   <entry id="10">
       <title>Distributed Ray Tracing</title>
       <year>1984</year>
       <authors>
          <author>Robert L. Cook</author>
          <author>Thomas Porter</author>
          <author>Loren Carpenter</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
             Ray tracing is one of the most elegant techniques in computer 
	     graphics. Many phenomena that are difficult or impossible with 
	     other techniques are simple with ray tracing, including shadows, 
	     reflections, and refracted light. Ray directions, however, have 
	     been determined precisely, and this has limited the capabilities 
	     of ray tracing. By distributing the directions of the rays 
	     according to the analytic function they sample, ray tracing can 
	     incorporate fuzzy phenomena. This provides correct and easy 
	     solutions to some previously unsolved or partially solved 
	     problems, including motion blur, depth of field, penumbras, 
	     translucency, and fuzzy reflections. Motion blur and depth of 
	     field calculations can be integrated with the visible surface 
	     calculations, avoiding the problems found in previous methods.  
       </abstract>
       <keywords></keywords>
       <pdf>library/p137-cook.pdf</pdf>
   </entry>
   <entry id="11">
       <title>Stochastic Sampling in Computer Graphics</title>
       <year>1986</year>
       <authors>
          <author>Robert L. Cook</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle>ACM Transactions on Graphics, Vol. 5, No. 1, January 1986, Pages 51-72.</fulltitle>
       <abstract>
            Ray tracing, ray casting, and other forms of point sampling 
	    are important techniques in computer graphics, but their 
	    usefulness has been undermined by aliasing artifacts. In 
	    this paper it is shown that these artifacts are not an 
	    inherent part of point sampling, but a consequence of using 
	    regularly spaced samples. If the samples occur at appropriate 
	    nonuniformly spaced locations, frequencies above the Nyquist 
	    limit do not alias, but instead appear as noise of the correct 
	    average intensity. This noise is much less objectionable to 
	    our visual system than aliasing. In ray tracing, the rays 
	    can be stochastically distributed to perform a Monte Carlo 
	    evaluation of integrals in the rendering equation. This is 
	    called distributed ray tracing and can be used to simulate 
	    motion blur, depth of field, penumbrae, gloss, and translucency.
       </abstract>
       <keywords>antialiasing, filtering, image synthesis, Monte Carlo integration, motion blur, raster graphics, ray tracing, sampling, stochastic sampling
</keywords>
       <pdf>library/p51-cook.pdf</pdf>
   </entry>
   <entry id="12">
       <title>Illumination for Computer Generated Pictures</title>
       <year>1975</year>
       <authors>
          <author>Bui Tuong Phong</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
          The quality of computer generated images of three-dimensional scenes 
	  depends on the shading technique used to paint the objects on the 
	  cathode-ray tube screen. The shading algorithm itself depends in 
	  part on the method for modeling the object, which also determines
      	  the hidden surface algorithm. The various methods of
     	  object modeling, shading, and hidden surface removal
     	  are thus strongly interconnected. Several shading techniques 
	  corresponding to different methods of object modeling and the 
	  related hidden surface algorithms are presented here. Human 
	  visual perception and the fundamental laws of optics are considered 
	  in the development of a shading rule that provides better quality 
	  and increased realism in generated images.                     
       </abstract>
       <keywords></keywords>
       <pdf>library/p311-phong.pdf</pdf>
   </entry>
   <entry id="13">
       <title>Models of Light Reflection for Computer Synthesized Pictures</title>
       <year>1977</year>
       <authors>
          <author>James F. Blinn</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
           In the production of computer generated 
           pictures of three dimensional objects, one stage 
           of the calculation is the determination of the 
           intensity of a given object once its visibility 
           has been established. This is typically done
           by modelling the surface as a perfect diffuser,
           sometimes with a specular component added for the
           simulation of hilights. This paper presents a
           more accurate function for the generation of
           hilights which is based on some experimental
           measurements of how light reflects from real
           surfaces. It differs from previous models in that
           the intensity of the hilight changes with the
           direction of the light source. Also the position
           and shape of the hilights is somewhat different
           from that generated by simpler models. Finally,
           the hilight function generates different results
           when simulating metallic vs. nonmetallic surfaces.
           Many of the effects so generated are somewhat
           subtle and are apparent only during movie
           sequences. Some representative still frames from
           such movies are included.
       </abstract>
       <keywords></keywords>
       <pdf>library/p192-blinn.pdf</pdf>
   </entry>
   <entry id="14">
       <title>Distribution-based BRDFs</title>
       <year>2006</year>
       <authors>
          <author>Michael Ashikhmin</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
          The bidirectional reflectance distribution function (BRDF) 
          formalism is commonly used in computer graphics to represent 
	  surface reflection properties. Although many BRDF models 
	  have been proposed, most do not possess at least some of 
	  the desirable practical properties. In this paper we present 
	  a simple and flexible model which satisfies many of these 
	  requirements. We show that the proposed model provides a 
	  good approximation for many real world materials, obeys basic 
	  physical restrictions, allows straightforward hardware 
	  implementation and provides for efficient sampling in a 
	  Monte-Carlo rendering system. A simple procedure to fit 
	  the model to BRDF measurement data is presented which 
	  suggests a simplified way of measuring surface reflection.
       </abstract>
       <keywords></keywords>
       <pdf>library/dbrdfs.pdf</pdf>
   </entry>
   <entry id="15">
       <title>An Irradiance Atlas for Global Illumination
             in Complex Production Scenes</title>
       <year>2004</year>
       <authors>
          <author>Per H. Christensen</author>
          <author>Dana Batali</author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
       We introduce a tiled 3D MIP map representation of global 
       illumination data. The representation is an adaptive,
       sparse octree with a "brick" at each octree node; each 
       brick consists of 8^3 voxels with sparse irradiance values.
       The representation is designed to enable efficient caching. 
       Combined with photon tracing and recent advances
       in distribution ray tracing of very complex scenes, the 
       result is a method for efficient and flexible computation of
       global illumination in very complex scenes. The method 
       can handle scenes with many more textures, geometry,
       and photons than could fit in memory. We show an example 
       of a CG movie scene that has been retrofitted with
       global illumination shading using our method.
       </abstract>
       <keywords></keywords>
       <pdf>library/irradiance_atlas.pdf</pdf>
       <www>http://graphics.pixar.com/index.html</www>
   </entry>
   <!--
   <entry id="4">
       <title></title>
       <year></year>
       <authors>
          <author></author>
       </authors>
       <fulltitle></fulltitle>
       <abstract>
       </abstract>
       <keywords></keywords>
       <pdf>library/.pdf</pdf>
   </entry>
   -->
</entries>
